<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Udeshya</title><link>https://udeshyadhungana.com.np/</link><description>Recent content on Udeshya</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://udeshyadhungana.com.np/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Linear Regression</title><link>https://udeshyadhungana.com.np/posts/2021-05-04-linear-regression/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://udeshyadhungana.com.np/posts/2021-05-04-linear-regression/</guid><description>Hello. Today I want to write about Linear Regression. It is basically the &amp;#34;Hello, World&amp;#34; program of Machine Learning. It is used to model the relationship between one or more inputs and a single output. Its application ranges from engineering to business. It is a process of learning from data. It falls under supervised learning category of Maching Learning. Regarding the algorithm, we have a set of inputs ($X$) and their corresponding outputs ($Y$).</description></item><item><title>The elegence of complex numbers</title><link>https://udeshyadhungana.com.np/posts/2020-10-14-complex-numbers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://udeshyadhungana.com.np/posts/2020-10-14-complex-numbers/</guid><description>Hey folks, today I want to write about a familiar topic in Higher mathematics, complex numbers, and in particular, the Euler&amp;rsquo;s formula. Complex Numbers show up in a number of different fields, like signal processing, electromagetism, quantum mechanics and many more. Though it&amp;rsquo;s a frequently occuring content, from what I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed, both the students and the experts are perplexed by complex numbers. For example, the beginners become puzzled by basic questions such as &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the meaning of $\sqrt{-1}$ ?</description></item><item><title>Vim for development</title><link>https://udeshyadhungana.com.np/posts/2020-08-12-vim-for-development/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://udeshyadhungana.com.np/posts/2020-08-12-vim-for-development/</guid><description>As a developer, I have this never ending thirst for productivity. On the journey of quinching this thirst, a few months ago, I stumbled upon a fantastic lecture on YouTube about Vim. After that, I started to use Vim. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t my first introduction to Vim though. I first came to know about it about an year ago. Still, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been able to use it as my main editor, because of one big problem: the learning curve.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://udeshyadhungana.com.np/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://udeshyadhungana.com.np/about/</guid><description>Hello there! I am a student of Computer Engineering at Pulchowk Engineering Campus, IOE. My interests are Data Science, Mathematics, Linux and teaching.
Skills Mathematics Linear Algebra Calculus Probability Theory Software Development NodeJs React React Native Django WordPress Data Science Machine Learning Linux / Unix Using as main operating system for 3 years Uses Arch btw Contact me Refer to the links in the homepage</description></item><item><title>Programs I Use</title><link>https://udeshyadhungana.com.np/programs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://udeshyadhungana.com.np/programs/</guid><description>I&amp;#39;ve been hooked to terminal based applications for quite a while now. They are fast, and a lot flexible compared to GUI programs. That&amp;#39;s not to say I completely avoid GUI applications. Both have their pros and cons. I think identifying the pros of both sides and developing the ability to harness them is best choice for the user.
Operating System I use Arch Linux. It&amp;#39;s a lightweight and flexible Linux distribution.</description></item></channel></rss>