<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on A minimal Hugo website</title><link>https://example.org/</link><description>Recent content in Home on A minimal Hugo website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building Abstractions using Functions</title><link>https://example.org/articles/2023-01-08-building-abstractions-with-functions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/articles/2023-01-08-building-abstractions-with-functions/</guid><description>If you have completed yet another 3-hour-long tutorial video on a new programming language and are well aware of basic concepts like variables, loops, functions, and arrays, but don’t know what to do next, well, this article is for you.
Let us begin with a wishful thinking. Don’t roll your eyes. Programming involves lots and lots of wishful thinkings. Assume that you’re an intern at a renowned company which specializes in numerical computation.</description></item><item><title>Linear Regression</title><link>https://example.org/articles/2021-05-04-linear-regression/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/articles/2021-05-04-linear-regression/</guid><description>Hello. Today I want to write about Linear Regression. It is basically the &amp;ldquo;Hello, World&amp;rdquo; program of Machine Learning. It is used to model the relationship between one or more inputs and a single output. Its application ranges from engineering to business. It is a process of learning from data. It falls under supervised learning category of Maching Learning. Regarding the algorithm, we have a set of inputs \(X\) and their corresponding outputs \(Y\).</description></item><item><title>The elegence of complex numbers</title><link>https://example.org/articles/2020-10-14-complex-numbers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/articles/2020-10-14-complex-numbers/</guid><description>Hey folks, today I want to write about a familiar topic in Higher mathematics, complex numbers, and in particular, the Euler&amp;rsquo;s formula. Complex Numbers show up in a number of different fields, like signal processing, electromagetism, quantum mechanics and many more. Though it&amp;rsquo;s a frequently occuring content, from what I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed, both the students and the experts are perplexed by complex numbers. For example, the beginners become puzzled by basic questions such as &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the meaning of \(\sqrt{-1}\) ?</description></item><item><title>Using Neovim for programming</title><link>https://example.org/articles/2020-08-12-vim-for-development/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/articles/2020-08-12-vim-for-development/</guid><description>As a programmer, I have this never ending thirst for productivity. On the journey of quinching this thirst, a few months ago, I stumbled upon a fantastic lecture on YouTube about Vim. After that, I started to use Vim. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t my first introduction to Vim though. I first came to know about it about an year ago. Still, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been able to use it as my main editor, because of one big problem: the learning curve.</description></item></channel></rss>